good morning let's start with the
meditation
and turn off your cell phone if you're
from Singapore
blow your nose
clear your throat smile
close your eyelid softly little bit of a
smile
settle down your shoulders maybe stretch
them a little bit push them back tighten
your stomachs like the abdomen relax
your fingers see if there's tension in
your forehead and when we start
meditating
don't let that tension come back
and then slowly come to your breath long
relaxed exhale
today we won't try to count the breath
just long relaxed exhales let us inhale
take care of it sir
please conduct with the teacher in your
heart inside a tiny space the size of a
grain of sugar deep in the center of
your heart and just check in say hi look
at them and join enjoy their present
now please think of what you drank this
morning maybe it was a glass of water
when you woke up maybe it was some juice
I had a nice coffee trying to picture
the glass or cup and liquid inside him
sitting on the table or a dresser
and then after you drink something there
with maybe a drop of water and juice
coffee clinging to the top of the cup
and it's just one job sitting on the
edge of the top try to focus tight down
on to that drop in your mind look at
that jump shape color maybe calmly it's
shining and what's it for just a minute
on that job just focus on that one job
of what you drink clinging to the top of
the cup try to bring your mind down to
that tiny space and let it fill your
mind
now think about how that job of water or
liquid which sustains all life how
special it is to have water or liquid
especially here in the desert such a
beautiful wonderful thing water liquid
which keeps all things alive spread
around our planet and here's a one drop
how amazing is water and then try to
imagine how it came from I imagine it
came from protecting life being careful
to drive carefully being careful not to
hurt other people keeping a vegetarian
way of life all of this
Karma's have created this drop of water
which is so precious and necessary for
us
just this one drop
to try to step back and appreciate how
that job of water is a picture in your
mind and when the Karma opens the
picture comes in front of your mind of a
drop and then your mind believes it is
outside on the cup but really that
picture is between your mind and the cup
presenting itself to your mind try to
appreciate that you're actually watching
a image perfect image perfect
functioning drop of water image in front
of your mind in front of your mind's eye
like you to step back one more step and
picture comics aim in your mind for me I
know it's at the heart but I for me it's
easier in my head if I imagine a tiny
seed in my head in the middle of my head
and then like a silver seed and then
tried to imagine that seed slowly
breaking open like an egg I guess and
then the image of the job of liquid an
accident that seen coming out of the
scene and then moving in front of your
mind's eye I for me it feels like it's
in my forehead or something that image
of a job exits the comic scene in my
head and then it moves in front of my
mind's eye and I see a drop of water
clinging to the rim of the cup top try
to just imagine that process silver
merci de karma breaks open a small image
of a job comes out moves in front of
your mind I I like to fill it up my
forehead and then I can see a drop of
liquid clinging to the rim of the cup
you can do that a few times
I'm not yet to please change the object
of your meditation to the Pacific ocean
the ocean between California and China
massive body of water many of us have
spent time at the ocean side looked
across the water from California you're
looking west to where the Sun sets one
of the most beautiful things in this
country's to see the sunset over the
Pacific Ocean standing on the beach and
I imagine in China and to stand on the
beach look across the out to the Pacific
Ocean and see the Sun come up over this
blue massive blue body of water that
touches much of the world some place is
very very deep I guess over a mile deep
and many hundreds of millions billions
of creatures living in that space born
living out their lives dying
leaving their bodies other preachers
being born from those same nutrients
many millions of years of life billions
upon billions of creatures
then please take your mind back to the
days when there was just earthen huge
hole no ocean yet
and then for millions of years rain fell
and drop by drop this Pacific Ocean was
created by forces as big as this planet
go back to the days when the planet was
just rock the first drops of rain
falling to begin the Pacific Ocean
and focus on the rain clouds and the
jobs falling down and try to imagine
they're also coming from your mind the
Pacific Ocean was created from your mind
billions of years ago try to feel the
same job by job coming out of your
silver karmic seeds coming before your
mind eyes and countless jobs of water
coming drop by drop out of seeds in your
own mind many 9 billion years ago to
create the blue ocean between America
and China
then please come back to the job of
liquid clinging to the top of a cup come
back to the tiny plumber at your heart
it's much smaller than that job thank
them and then come to your breath watch
three slow exhale each exhale sharing
the good karma of this meditation with
people on both sides of the ocean and
everywhere else
and then you can slowly open your eyes
take a good stretch
any questions I'm done no good let's go
we have a lot to do today I'm gonna try
to catch up so we're going to be here
for a while
I hope we were talking about meditation
number 26 I think summed up come
blessing that number two it was the last
one in the old in the old book and the
last thing we did was a poem from
Sartain the Lamas name was Sartain yeah
the the poem is called the prayer to see
her lovely face or something like that
very beautiful poem why were they
talking about a ship huh yeah
crossing the ocean what's the ocean
yelling husband kids who don't behave
it's traffic that doesn't go the way you
want
okay what's the ship
Thank You mr. okay get you across and
it's the diamond cutter suit or the ship
now
it's the idea again and citrus just some
paper or recording that contains the
idea okay but still we give the name to
the sutra what did the Buddha give them
him yeah professionalism I think my Lama
will say oh Aaron is your elected
representative this morning she's
getting all the answers that's his way
of criticizing the rest of us okay just
a few more notes on that and then we can
start coming here three and we're on
schedule don't worry we will finish come
I see the tree
maybe we'll be up all night but that's
okay
by the way I had the four language
things when you don't forget I'll just
throw it towards cinta so it's your job
to fix to fix the Chinese one more time
the Norfolk State Department sends one
more time and we'll try to give it to
people tomorrow okay
it's nice Massacre Moschino makes the
point that this is really all six three
sections okay it's not just the
profession of wisdom
maybe the Buddha should have called the
book the six perfections okay not just
the perfection of wisdom okay
he could have called it all six
perfections okay and he says you know
later Buddha's going to ask the question
or subdue T says why is it so why why
why is it the perfection of wisdom
and then you have to think that even
that idea of foods and images is coming
from you okay the perfection of wisdom
is coming from you okay not just the
paper of the book but the ideas in the
book are coming from you okay then then
you have the right then your
understanding doesn't make you fall out
of your understanding we keep saying it
doesn't spit you out of your
understanding understand that your
understanding is also coming from you
and mainly by sharing this with other
people in a way which doesn't bother
other people okay there's an idea here
come a Sheila mentioned it and then he
comes back to it later called number
crimson what's done
what's numbed on DARPA DARPA sure comes
up yeah pure fake real fake gender jaada
jaada gender real fake sorry yeah real
no real thing
the fake thing which is real okay now
we'll talk about it later okay generally
speaking most of the world you
experience is fake it means it's
tricking you okay especially when you're
emotional or you're tired it looks like
your husband is decide to yell at you
okay we call it illusion that's the
meaning of illusion in Buddhism okay
looks like husband decided to yell at
you but the reality is it's coming from
you okay so everything is lying to you
in Buddhism we call it deceptive reality
everything is lying to a normal person
everything is lying when a person with
understanding looks at the same thing
they don't
to deny they just seem real okay now
there's two kinds of fake things right
real ones and sake sake sakes and real
things okay
just if you're interested this is a I
think it's a Swatantra idea but like
it's you're really jealous husband or
wife let's say you're really jealous
wife and your husband is you know you
come home and your husband's like this
you know you know and then you feel
jealous you think oh he's texting
somebody he met at work or something
like that you know then you build the
whole thing in your mind you know he's
texting this kid lady I saw at his work
and you know then for 24 hours you can't
think about anything else you know you
your your little bit grumpy you know
he's like good evening honey and you're
like yeah good evening you know and then
you go to bed and he falls asleep
he's always snoring mom then you check
his phone and he was on Alibaba buying
you a birthday present
okay Phyllis buying you a birthday
present
do you learn the whole food for our
story I made in my mind it was fake
thing okay got it
that's fake thing what's the real thing
you could say the phone but you can say
the order are not Obama for your
birthday present okay that's correct
that was correct they're both fake yeah
that and you think that when you found
the real one the Alibaba order that also
you think it's coming from outside so we
call real thing
okay got it fake real but we're not
going to talk about it now but we just
did okay
he talked about it later
then the Sidra goes on you know not just
a Buddhist wisdom not just the
perfection of wisdom is coming from us
but also the Buddhist speech when the
Buddha speaks it's coming from us then
the last thing in common lucila to is a
meditation about a car and I somehow I
got lost
it's not income or two anymore
it was it was like number 47 I cut them
it got lost so maybe it can be a secret
transmission the to income ratio to
income ratio 3 there's a missing
meditation okay it's called the car
those of you who did it DCI level 7
yeah oh it's in your book oh it's in the
old book yeah okay so I'm going to cover
it and those of you who don't have it
maybe you can draw a car and you're in
your reading okay because the last
question in Cumberland number two the
Buddha says to Cebu T is there any
Dharma which the Buddha talked
it's a Buddhist says no there isn't any
male okay no there aren't it is no okay
then somebody says you none of the
Dharma you ever taught ever existed at
all okay meaning master karma Sheila
says he likes to use the word ultimate
ultimately there doesn't exist any
teaching you ever gave okay then what
does ultimate mean and master kumla
Sheila talks about it okay
and this is a famous
the stinking called Ronson and Chetan
okay say Ronson Tintin
Langton Tintin Ron ten means rocket
Enoch it means let's start teacher G 10
means cheating you okay then if I ask
you what is this thing I remember the
first cell phone I had it was a Motorola
someone gave it to me it was old one
it's the flip open one you they gave it
to me I here at Diamond Mountain and I'm
like what I do and they said you don't
know how to use a cell phone I think I
was 10 years without a phone and I'm
like no I I don't know how to use it and
they took me to suffer and we went to
the phone store and they're all talking
this foreign language you knowing about
the cell phone I couldn't understand
anything and the first couple of
messages I sent to V I sent to everybody
and it was embarrassing
I remember Anatole wrote me and said get
lucky okay
you know I'm sorry so you have a how you
recognize a thing as a phone yeah it
didn't look like a phone to me
a phone should have two big parts and
you hold it here and you know you put it
on the thing and you know it took me a
while to think of it as a fun it's great
it's a problem you know and my friends
talk like that I'm still trying to go
like this and you know so you have a
picture in your mind
phone when I say phones you have a
picture in your mind come I said phone
and then BOOM what's the Chinese from
Foreman
Shoji Shoji
I think show didn't let's get your
cousin your mind okay
probably it's what your mom told you
that the phone
your mom was picking up this thing if
you're young like some of you guys she's
got her cell phone and when I say shorty
you you teacher comes in your mind our
phone you know it's called a kitchen
knife syndrome CS Lewis calls it that
famous Christian writer you when you're
a little kid you go to your friend's
house for dinner and and they have a
knife kitchen knife and you say what's
that and your friend says that's a
kitchen knife and then you say that's
not a kitchen knife that's not a kitchen
knife at our house our kitchen knife is
different
it's that kitchen back there yeah yeah
everybody has their own kitchen knife
doing that it's a big thing when you're
a kid you know wow there's two kinds of
kitchen knives you know so you have a
picture in your mind usually it's the
one your mom gave you okay that's a
phone that's a car we call that a car
okay that picture in in psychology they
call archetype archetype mr. young from
Germany call you who was a student of a
yachtie major Eliana who was my teachers
teacher but anyway they have an idea
that in the human mind there are
teachers that you are born with this old
old pictures you know and for your whole
life you have picture of a car
maybe it's your mom's car you know and
for you that's that car when I say car
you get that picture in your mind that's
called archetype in psychology in
Buddhism it's called chitin
archetype Qi means general ten means
like definition okay general definition
of a car for you is this picture of the
first car your mom showed you something
like that that's called Chetan it's just
a picture in your mind that picture
comes up when I say car okay when I say
car who made the connection between the
word car and that picture yeah it's not
natural
okay it's not didn't come from nature
it's artificial
you could call car ten that picture you
can call parent it there's no you could
use any word you can call it boo boo boo
boo boo okay I'm driving my booty
booga dooga you know and if your mom
told you that's the word for that
picture you will always say I'm driving
my brother good but good you know it
just random which word you choose okay
but the archetype is it's there the
picture in your mind okay where do they
come from
what architects come from out of his
coma seat out of that silver seed like
the archetype of when I say water drop
you have a picture in your mind of water
jump right that comes out of the karmic
seed okay so who made a car what's a car
made of pictures where did it come from
seeds
how did you plant that scene you were
the transportation director at Diamond
Mountain you got many people to the
Tucson Airport okay you need a lot of
those seeds to have a car especially in
Hong Kong where the car costs three
times normal or Singapore where it costs
four times normal you know you need a
little you need to give a lot of people
rides if you want to have a car okay so
that car picture is coming out of here
karma see now if a car existed out there
take any particular car take your car
the car you you have like John Brady's
supercar okay with someone gave to him
by the way you get to have this a car
okay that's a car got it this one is car
that that his car is a car okay my car a
car then you think it's outside pictures
inside car
John car is in the parking lot it's not
here in his mind okay got it
that's called Ronson the the conch the
expression of the idea car okay the
expression the example of the chicken of
the picture okay does John have car yes
he has to what's the first one car where
is that word Park then he has a wrong
turn car he has a car out in the parking
lot okay that's the real one that's the
expression of the picture it's out in
the parking lot okay now you're ready
for the punchline common-law Sheila says
the wrong pen is the cheetah the car out
in the parking lot is the car John's
head again he says that did to divide
them is a sauce okay when I say a car
and a picture comes in your mind then I
say John's car on the parking lot you
have to realize I'm talking about the
same thing
John's car out in the parking lot is
parked in his mind got it John's car out
in the parking lot
exist as a picture in his mind it's a
chicken got it so car and John's car and
John's car John's mind are all the same
got it
you you got a maybe you can meditate on
that yeah
sorry off me
while in the same more radical okay why
are you talking about that
because this is how master Kamla Sheila
explains it when somebody says you never
taught any dumber
at all or in in today's example John
never parked his car in the parking lot
a guy got it yeah good okay we can say a
sudden this question yeah the question
was I forget me
yeah what was the closest yeah is it the
same thing and I said exactly the same
thing yeah same in in bulletin we said
same coverage Kabakov a chick they are
the same they occupy the same space yes
alright once I talking about
mmm-hmm hang on oh yeah
so when the bird is like the Buddha says
there is no Dharma at all it's the same
as saying there's no car in the parking
lot okay
there's no John's car in the parking lot
I got it
even in the parking lot yes Connie
looking John's head for the car keys now
she should go look out the car okay
but but in the end the wrong turn is to
teach him that the car in the parking
lot is the car in John's mind and fun by
the way if every question you ask you
are losing the end of common lishchyna 3
no pressure
so it might sound a stupid question but
it is the same why it feels so much
different yeah my fat my tampon we
talked about it yesterday you know why
should we worry about it
who cares you can drive it either way
you can use it to get to Tucson okay who
cares if it's an image in my mind or if
it's an outside thing and the answer is
if it's an image you could keep his car
going forever like my car which is from
the early 1900's and if you understand
that the car is coming from helping
other people get rides you will loan
your car to say gee for the whole
retreat so that it will last longer okay
if you don't understand that cheats in
Islington you will say I'm not going to
learn my car to somebody else because
they will get banged up it's our mum
garden okay that's why that's why it's
important you can have eternal happiness
okay somebody else had a question I
guess you cancelled it no microphone
microphone no more I don't understand
how the comic seat in your mind comes
from your first Motorola handy you never
see before a Motorola handy you never
saw a car before unique like that yeah
yeah okay this is a famous question in
Buddhism your mom wouldn't show you your
first car if you didn't give rides in
your past life understand the reason
your mom showed you your first car once
you gave rides in your past life well
geshe-la where did that car come from
the life before where did that car come
from the life before case law doesn't
make sense according to that I've had
endless cars beginningless cars that's
right
okay and science is wrong there was no
first car okay there's no big thing
nowadays they're talking about Big Bang
number two which creates Big Bang number
one and I guess in 20 years some
physicists at Oxford will say I think
there was a big bang number three you
know to create the second big thing you
know okay
no energy without energy before
conservation energy basic Newton law
come on okay if there's one big bang
something has to make it happen duh okay
here we go now you want to go deeper
this is commonly Sheila
he is merciless he won't let one word
girl he says by the way sir Billy says
so but he didn't say you never taught
any Dhamma
he said you never taught any Dharma at
all so why did Cebu tea say at all you
know like he can't let one word go you
know and then he says at all is to
eliminate any other possibility other
than cheats in and runs okay either
John's car is wrong 10 out in the
parking lot or John's cars cheats and in
his mind either the Dharma that the
Buddha taught is in the books that you
hold in your hand or the Dharma that the
Buddha taught is a picture in your mind
but there's no other possibility
okay it's only 210 and nonsense okay
that's why the Buddha said at all
okay no third possibility we say in
Tibetan Adam what's third possibility
yeah boom Zumba there's no pool Simba
either it's a picture in your mind or
it's a car out in the parking lot
there's not a possibility
so Cebu tee says you didn't teach any
drama at all okay got it
just nod if you're lost not if you're
lost and not if you understand okay all
right we covered it this is by the way
where Camila Sheila says because this
section is about not studying other
Dharma he said the idea other
explanations of where cars came from are
mistaken and they are not our group
there are other others other teachings
okay even if they're written by a
Buddhist got it they are outside
explanations meaning they're just
totally wrong cars are made of iron cars
were invented by Henry Ford those are
totally wrong okay okay and and he
equates outside explanations outside
religions outside beliefs like science
he says they're hung up on size outside
guys are hung up on science what's that
mean they think the cars coming from the
other time they think the husband is
angry from the other side okay so we can
call them other ciders or we can call
them outsiders
generally other side or outsider means
non-buddhist but for Camila Sheila I
don't know a Muslim a Jew a Hindu who
understands the pen is inside and a
Buddhist in a temple with
Rosen who doesn't understand the pen is
outside or a scientist who tells you
cars are made of chemicals and minerals
and they're outside got it
because their other side all right now
something sexy
what's irishman mean Irishman you should
know because you're our Vedic doctor huh
so is means our life Ayurvedic
F changes to our b4v okay is better
because our your Veda it's the science
of life meaning Indian medicine ancient
Indian medicine okay so I use means time
life money means to possess okay
as they're ending as a suffix it means
to possess okay so what's Irishman who
has time who has time sebou T in the
Sutra countless times is called Irishman
sebou tea wine Irishman Irishman long a
Irishman come on what's the English
Jimmy he's always called junior monk
okay junior monk the monk who has time
means the monk who has time left to go
it means bitty month okay new month
throughout the Sutra he's called
Irishman baby junior mom okay it's like
an insult
okay said in Den Bosch re boo say
remember sue sue booty telling them Bob
George okay that the person who has time
left to go before he becomes a senior
monk okay
lots of people mistook it they
translated it as senior monk okay that's
a mistake number one
then if you read commercial ah someday
okay in this section
he calls Cebu T Nathan study era star
Villa elder monk he slips it in if
you're not sensitive you won't notice it
he says this time here of Cebu T by and
in this section he graduates ability to
see your mom okay who decided Carmel
Angela he decided we can't call this guy
junior monkey anymore he just explained
she sends in the wrong sense he's an
elder okay Nathan study no means elder
there's a famous spirit to the sixteen
star Venus
it's a traditional prayer for a long
life of your nama okay they tend to do
the 16 de villiers for example buckle on
people like that
I studied a little bit with with this
generation buckler Rinpoche so from the
time of the Buddha there are sixteen
elders okay so he refuses to call Cebu T
junior monk he says career question
Chinese translation amount into the one
with long life yeah I never thought I
didn't ever see this explanation yeah I
don't think so
it's a traditional word for junior okay
got it
yeah that's why we're that's why you're
going to read translate all this stuff
okay also you can say that they had a
reason to translated that way to help
people they had special wisdom and they
translated it that way to help people
it's possible it's better to think like
that okay when your llama makes a
mistake for you it's better to say oh he
must have done that on purpose to teach
me something all right
I think we're on - we finished the car
now we can start conversing or three
okay and we're gonna finish college okay
I promise but if we don't die before
maybe even if we do die okay
the first meditation income less you
know three it's kind of the name is long
it's called my breakfast and the birth
of the universe did you ever hear about
this subject like half an hour ago
okay that was the meditation you did
this morning okay breakfast is the drop
of liquid orange juice coffee water
lemon hot lemon water okay and the birth
of the universe is the Pacific Ocean
first raindrops completely equal it's a
Buddhist like vehicle me Ambani summit
are there no different
okay you're created the drop of orange
juice sitting on the top of the class
this morning this morning and you
created the birth of this planet
billions of years ago okay yum bunny
Samata equally no difference okay
it did harder to create a planet in a
glass of orange juice apparently not
okay you did bro takes my karma yeah you
have done bull okay but geshe-la that
was billions of years ago you know I was
born in nineteen I was born hundred
years ago me and Susan but anyway some
of you were born after the Beatles so
anyway that's how I date things I hate
it when I say that Beatle song in there
going what Beatles yeah you created
things that were set in motion billions
of years ago you got to get used to that
okay for you to study
diamond cutter Sutra at at Diamond
Mountain Retreat Centre first you had to
create this planet and you did okay just
a small time gap a couple how many
billion years I don't know home
people are always correcting me for four
billion years okay so you set in motion
the events of the creation of this
planet I wish you would have made more
trees here but maybe you can do it later
you've made the planet so you could have
this teaching understand okay you made
the whole planet and four shemitah today
your Shama texercise is called Bell
Margot mistake belma's gumball Belmar
Kumba so Belle mom means fiery one
that's the name my llama gate to a
certain nun at diamond I don't know why
but it also if you spell it a different
way
spel okay rather than DP al okay
it means alternating meditation okay
alternating meditation so today during
your meditations for the rest of the day
I want you to practice Belmar Goomba
Velma means alternate cosmic atomic
cosmic atomic cause me atomic flip it
okay
up and down go to the creation of the
universe and come back to the last drop
of pipi this morning something like that
okay I like the big weird little things
in my house this morning it was penny
gave me a t-shirt in in Guam in court
and it has this irritating label inside
I don't know why they put scratchy
labels on the inside right where my
bellybutton
you know scratchy label so meditate on
the label inside your t-shirt you know
write this come from was it from Hong
Kong or was it for me or was it from
Hong Kong because it was from me okay go
to that little label on your or go to
one letter on the label then go to I
don't know Mount Everest or something
okay go to something big alright the Sun
who made the Sun okay go to the Sun stay
at the Sun for a while then come back to
I don't know the fingernail clipping
that you clipped off last night I
clipped my fingernails last night and I
was feeling guilty to dump him in
Kelsey's house he's not here he
I thought she'll step on them you know
so I'm crawling around the floor looking
for them maybe I left one so that's a
tiny thing right then go back to the
universe you know who made Jupiter
Jupiter's in the sky nowadays you guys
got to have this app right what's it
called sky guide yeah it's really cool
it makes new age music and when you go
like this it moves around and it shows
you the name of every star and when you
touch the star it gives you the history
of the star okay very cool you can see
stars that are in China right now it
sees through the earth okay so what's it
going sky guide I think it's free or
it's one dollar and something ridiculous
cool okay so do tell ma Gama that's your
assignment today yesterday you mastered
listening to your heartbeat
you're the the sound of the air going
through your nose so you shouldn't blow
your nose just leave the boogers in
there and there's more noise it's easier
to hear okay just kidding
we had teacher training Sedona College
they told me disma we watched your
videos you have to stop picking your
nose you know and the sound of your
blood in your ears okay so that was
yesterday you can do more of that today
but today do some palmar Goomba okay
certainly then master Camila Sheila
calls it disappearing and appearing
disappearing and appearing
okay disappearing means in English
shopping okay we call deconstruction
break it down break it down
deconstruction okay deconstruct things
it's a typical problem-solving method
okay
like somebody bought me this scott
lorida bot me this cleaning robot thing
it's about this big cleans your house
and people give me a lot of stuff and I
have a really small house so there's a
steady flow to the Goodwill store and it
was very close to the Goodwill store bag
I said ah maybe I'll just try it once
you know and then I couldn't understand
how to turn on you know and so I did
constructed you know I said the buttons
not on the bottom the buttons not on the
side the button must be on the top
probably they put it in the middle oh
look at work and after the first time I
cleaned my house forget it it's my best
friend you know it cleans under the bed
it goes everywhere I can translate books
he's working I gave him a name garbanzo
and so you have to be constructing you
have to break things down when you have
a problem you know you don't know how to
work something like especially computer
stuff break it down you know break it
down so Buddha breaks down he uses
deconstruction he says sebou tea if you
had a whole planet and you broke it down
into dust pieces whole planet and you
broke it down into dust pieces would
that be a lot of pieces and somebody's
like yeah okay then come by feels like
why does Buddha such a stupid question
you know break down the whole planet the
idea is deconstruction deconstruction
break things down break things down and
then they disappeared
okay break it down in your mind my
husband's not nice to me nowadays my
husband called me bad news okay break it
down what'd he say words what kind of
words bad words yeah
Kenner Shakur come from a banana seat no
doesn't she come for equality yes
watermelon right oh then maybe bad word
come from bad word maybe maybe I said
bad words to my kids last league yeah
maybe then you deacons chart your
husband's criticism deconstruct you can
start deconstruct and then suddenly
because you deconstructed it it
disappears okay it disappears oh it's no
longer my husband's criticism it my
husband's criticism melted it crumbled
it fell into pieces like a planet into
dust and then it's gone
there is no criticism from husband
coming from me okay because start
because turn that's the white Buddhist
talking about planners okay then he says
by the way go down to the Adams okay go
down to those particles the dust after
you blew up a planet in two pieces of
dust do they exist deconstruct them
deconstruct the the drop of water on
your on your glance take it apart okay
when you when I say Adam although in
juice molecule orange juice okay
then you think there's a little ball
called oyster juice element number 112
okay and you see it when I say Adam you
see a little picture in your mind a
little ball it has a left side and a
right side right
but when you undo construct them you put
them back together right then it's got
to be there's one out I'm here and
there's another atom over here there's
like how many 1 2 3 4 5 6 sides and
they're all touching each other but
where do they touch each other on the
side geshe-la how big is the side I
don't know it's probably a whole atom
one how could I let them touch a whole
atom does the left side of one atom that
touches the right side of another atom
to the left side of the setup touch the
the other side of the other atom like or
do they just stuck in one place or do
they touch all around how much touches
well they just touch guys know how much
these atoms how can have a piece of
another atom means up thumb means it's
from Sanskrit dum means to divide up
thumb means indivisible you can't split
it there's no less than right side of an
atom oh so the left side atom touches
the right side arm right then it's
nothing it's impossible
atom is impossible okay deconstruct
deconstruct even atom deconstructed oh
it's a quark geshe-la
it had spin lesbian right spinach corn
you know it has charm pieces I'm Adam
come on Adam means indivisible okay
scientists then they're going to come up
with the charm of determine the clerk of
the court
give it up honey okay there's no good
ever okay not possible
where is it coming from yeah something
good you do if it's orange juice it's
coming from good karma if it's eggplant
juice it's coming from back home okay
I'm telling you okay
now the things that disappear when you
examine them they appear when you
understand they're coming from you
got it so Camila Sheila's big into this
idea things disappear when you
deconstruct them
then they reappear when you see them
popping out of your karmic seeds got it
now you understand the whole name of the
meditation what is it
breakfast and birth in the universe
that's easy we did it this morning
completely equal the Pacific Ocean and
the last drop of orange juice in your
cup both coming from you okay billions
of years old and and 10 seconds home
okay disappearing when you check them
you can't when you break that planet
into atoms and you try to find the left
side right side atom it's not there okay
everything disappears outside John's car
in the parking lot disappears then how
does it reappear you understand its
popping out of a seat are you
comfortable just not if you're lost not
also okay and so then it is here in the
end things work atoms work cards work
cuz they come from being nice to other
people got it then they're here if you
don't believe John's cards there when he
leaves the parking lot you stand in
front of the car John you can accelerate
okay
and break your leg and then you say oh
car really works huh huh okay and the
bill you get will also be real from the
hospital okay oh by the way this is an
old this cellmark bomba going from big
stuff to small stuff is a big method of
modern science okay quantum physics the
behavior of smallest particles and how
does that reflect the behavior of
planets and galaxies and light crossing
the galaxy okay the bending of light the
proof of relativity okay like scientists
have that there's a cool method in
science you know we can understand more
about how light was born and how
comes from the Sun if we if we measure
how atoms move in an accelerator and how
they can be bent that the path pathway
can be bent or you can watch the bending
of light past mercury you can it was one
of the early proofs of relativity is
that when sunlight passes by mercury it
gets slightly bent and you can measure
it by the time it gets to earth you see
so by observing big things like Pacific
Oceans is you can understand drops of
water okay so Buddha likes to
deconstruct and we do the same thing so
today in your meditation you're going to
Belmar go from big to little big to
little and it it keeps you awake it
keeps your mind strong okay and it's a
trick it's an old meditation trick if
you get tired of planets then come to
the drop that's coming down your nose
right now in meditation not supposed to
move you're supposed to let it drip on
your lap you can tell a really good
meditator because they have little drops
on their lap they're okay maybe it's
something else going on okay so I think
we covered that with me that was a long
one right yeah by the way those of you
who know the force basis meditations and
you're lying against the earth you can
imagine creating the earth right
creating the forces that created the big
bang that created the dust that created
the earth okay so you also get credit
for things that happen billions of years
ago not just your husband yelling at you
this evening okay you you created the
planet that your husband's standing on
okay all right then all that comes back
kumla Sheila points out to the idea of
paradises when we talked about paradises
meaning big vision let your mind go big
okay don't get hung up on you know
problems with your part
problems with your dog problems with
your work don't let your mind get stuck
in little things okay bigger stuff is
going on okay in that billion years of
history your boss is not very important
at work don't get hung up don't speak at
this level a boss go bigger sometimes go
smaller
your boss is yelling at you there's spit
coming out his mouth
look at the bubbles oh that also came
from me don't get stuck on this level of
someone who's hurting you giving you a
bad time okay all right and then
ultimately the coolest long term vision
thing is when you see emptiness directly
and if you're on a bodhisattva trying
you will see every living being in the
universe in five minutes your mind
already has the capacity to see every
living being not just this world not the
billions who living in the ocean little
guys but your mind has the ability to
see every living being on every ocean in
every world okay at the same time within
five minutes your mind has this capacity
your mind is not linear your mind
doesn't really work one by one your mind
can multitask countless billions at the
same time your mind has this ability
when you see emptiness directly and you
have your first direct experience of
bodhichitta
that's vision you will see every living
creature within five minutes the face of
every living creature because you love
them okay the motivation is the love for
them okay so if you have that strong of
a love you get to see them got it cool
that's buddy chiller all right I'm going
to do one more before your duty break
and the first drop of water that comes
on
and run a new section they can shape a
chip attorney no Chara means thanking
the Buddha
okay section 11 in commonly she loves
how many 18 sections by the way 12 of
those are the most important
they're called the antidotes okay so
we're on this new section number 11 and
this is where Buddha repeats the
question if you saw somebody with the
science that only a Buddha has does that
make them a Buddha we say no not until
your mind glues them together because
you thank the Buddha in the pack okay if
you thank the Buddha in the past you
create karma that karma glues together
the signs and you can see Buddhist okay
dad seconds finished
[Music]
it's not very long it's only a few pages
okay I'm going to go to section which
number 12
okay section 12 it's about veer virya
effort working hard
Buddhist working hard hard Buddhist
working my Lama used to point to our
neighbor who spent many days under his
car trying to fix it many many days he
said that's hard work but it's not vilya
that's not good effort
that's a waste of time okay effort means
the real meaning of effort is what
somebody give me the Tibetan tongue hung
gay son Gandhi Latoya or say some guns
Galya
whoo-hoo cigar Santee demo master Sarah
Miller what is hard work is to enjoy
doing good things hard work means enjoy
doing good things
okay then this section is about learning
to overcome tiredness when you feel
tired in your practice
maybe you feel tired of trying to deal
with your husband or your boss or your
wife okay this is learning to not feel
tired this whole section 12 is learning
to not feel tired okay
then there's a second part to that okay
learning not to have the wrong idea
about not feeling tired okay I don't
feel tired don't think like that
I don't feel tired bolting like that
okay I did it
don't think like that coming from your
seat
okay so not feeling tired and then
understanding why you don't feel tired
okay I'm gonna go for another can you
guys it's 20 minutes okay okay then what
beauty thing if somebody has to go just
go okay I'm okay with that
I know you're going outside to make a
cell phone call it's okay
don't forget your cell phone if you
gotta go go okay in this next section
I'll read it to you because it's very
sweet and then by the sheer power of the
teaching the junior monks of Booty began
to cry and then he wiped his eyes and he
said to Lord Buddha this time a cutter
suture he Kelly called because at this
presentation of the Dharma it's amazing
okay this is just amazing and ever since
I got wisdom I never heard such a cool
Dharma I never heard such a diamond like
that this is amazing
ever since I got with them it means ever
since I had my experience of emptiness
directly since then I never heard a
teaching like this okay the implication
is to appreciate what's happening in a
diamond cutter Sutra it helps if you're
an ayah it helps if you saw emptiness
directly so the birdies are saying I
heard many Dharma teachings after I saw
emptiness directly but this one you just
don't give it up every single thing you
say you're talking about emptiness
emptiness emptiness emptiness this is a
real aria teacher I like it where where
he starts to cry and change this
you designed a whole Sutra just for
arias man buddy stuff arias this is so
cool you know I never I've been waiting
for this you know okay this is special
okay so commerce here talks about we
call it in the reading and arias the
tears of an ayah okay
Nanaia it means do you really understand
that every single word in the diamond
cutter Sutra Jim country is about
function
it's about emptiness Buddha doesn't say
one normal thing okay and and in any
Buddhism we call it tonguing what's
tonguing yeah sometimes the Buddha got a
chance to say what he felt like saying
and sometimes he had to dumb it down
okay
sometimes he got a special audience you
know he got a good chance like locked up
in diamond mountain retreat center
special people from all over the room
the best of the best
you know Dan he's so happy Buddha so
happy now I could say what I really want
to say emptiness emptiness emptiness
emptiness emptiness okay then it go on a
DTI tour I'll be nice to people you know
[Music]
okay so we call tongue in tongue means
to dumb it down for people and me means
Buddha gets to say what Buddha wants to
say but I just want to talk about karmic
seeds pictures John's car in the parking
lot actually that's what Buddha wants to
talk about so in this future the
audience is special and in the audience
here today is special okay you are
special you are one out of a hundred
million people okay really I'm not just
complimenting you my close friends no I
never compliment anybody but you are
amazing if you're if you're made it here
you're amazing okay it's you're better
than a person who win the gold medal at
the Olympics
those are many they give many people get
done okay you're amazing if you made it
in this room you're amazing
then when you do this meditation in your
cottage okay when you get to this
meditation trying to think of how many
things you remember about the diamond
color Sutra okay if you ask Jessie
Michael you know Geshe Michael what do
some of the highlights of the diamond
cutter Sutra I'm like well I like the
part where the king of Kong cars cutting
off the guy's fingers and I remember the
part that if you study this Sutra you're
going to get headaches and car accidents
and it I like to explain all my bad
karma this money that's good karma and I
remember you know then just during this
meditation highlights of the diamond
cutter Sutra okay things you remember a
Buddha talks about giving away your body
millions of times Buddha talks about
planet dissolve into dust and okay
then ask yourself a question when he
talked about the king of culling cause I
always remember this calling card which
don't exist anymore I don't know but
anyway when he talks about king of Kong
Kong it's all of our emptiness it's all
about emptiness how oh he says if the
guy didn't understand emptiness he would
have got upset at the king okay the guy
was getting his fingers cut off if he
didn't understand Kong he would have
grown up said oh well how does it
connect with when the Buddha talks about
the headaches you're going to get oh
that's like understanding emptiness
short-circuits my bad seeds from many
years in the past and they open in
imperfectly
okay like that so in doing this
meditation in your cottage today think
about the pieces of the diamond cutter
you remember and then why did Cebu tea
cry about that piece because it was
talking about emptiness well how and
then ask yourself a question okay cool
then think about how goddamn lucky you
are and start to cry a little bit that
means you're doing good okay if you
can't do that cut an onion during the
meditation okay okay all right
and when you start to cry don't be proud
if tears come sometimes I start to cry I
think about my Lama ISM and I start to
cry then I think I hope everybody sees
I'm crying about my long run you know
it's human nature right so be careful
when you have realizations when cool
things happen to you after a hundred
days of nothing happening in India okay
then don't ruin it but I said you know
I'm so cool I had something cool happen
to me I must be special like then you
get kicked out then you have another 100
days nothing just dry no realization
it's nothing special
okay very cool day you're having
meditation you'll have 10 bad days okay
I'm sorry but don't don't be surprised
it's normal the people here who've done
three-year retreat ask them how many
really good days you had out of the
sounds and don't say I don't know maybe
six
but you wouldn't have the six without
the Thompson you know that okay all
right we're going to take a pee-pee
break there all right we're on
meditation them between the Buddha just
said o conquerer any living being who
can think correctly of the suture that
you have just taught is wondrous in the
highest and why is it so because o
conquer this same correct thinking is
something that could never exist and
this is precisely why those gone does
have spoken about thinking correctly or
what we call thinking correctly okay
that's the diamond cutter Sutra and the
picture okay always stick to the
pictures okay on the plane home try to
see how many pictures you can remember
and then connecting the idea to the
pictures not very difficult okay this
guy that I chose I bought the photo okay
all these photos properly mostly and he
just looks like Keanu Reeves on a good
day so he's thinking about his
understanding of emptiness
what's the Buddha always say after that
as much as he has okay
as much as understanding as he has it
means ninety percent eighty percent ten
percent he's thinking about his
understanding okay
and he's understanding that his
understanding of emptiness is also empty
okay he's understanding
that he's understanding more and more
because he's been sharing it with other
people
okay that's the cost of understanding
more okay and it doesn't mean being a
missionary we call proselytizing don't
bother people with your Buddhism okay
but if someone's having trouble with
their husband you don't have to call it
Buddhism you could just say well I
notice you've been yelling at your kids
a lot lately to maybe a son connection
you know I don't know okay like that all
right and then when you share with them
I think especially in a in a friendly
happy way with with people who trust you
then you create seeds to understand more
okay so your understanding that the
reason the reason for this picture is
that this guy is is understanding his
understanding okay
goddess he knows where it comes from and
when it gets stuck in the diamond cutter
city I just don't get this thing about
John's car look John even left he didn't
understand about the clinic spite
checking on his car so it is still not
there okay then now commonly Sheila says
when you misunderstand your
understanding what do we call it and he
answers himself he says attachment okay
so when you get deeper into Buddhism
your understanding of attachment gets
deeper okay
most people think all British shouldn't
have a good car
our Buddhists shouldn't have a good
house or Buddhists shouldn't wear nice
clothes or Buddhists shouldn't wear
expensive clothes or something like that
Buddha should be voluntarily unhappy and
deprived and then your religious okay
that the ultimate idea a Brit ISM is to
enjoy what's the Sanskrit word for the
name of the Buddhist body in his own
paradise or her own paradise some vulgar
kya the body of enjoying this paradise
that tsongkhapa's in it's not like I
said right cement floor building you
know with no furniture and cold and
there's mold on the walls
that's not religious okay dress night
it's okay you know this the coolest
dress wear silk stuff that's okay that's
alright
shouldn't I give away all my money to
poor people give away give away a lot
keep some and buy nice things it's okay
okay it's all right
she'd be happy okay so the higher
meaning of attachment is you think it
doesn't come from sharing okay you
that's the real meaning of attachment do
I have attachment I don't know where do
you think the good clothes come from
where do you think the trip to Hawaii
comes from it comes from sharing giving
to others okay then you're not attached
to the trip to Hawaii then you can
really enjoy the trip to Hawaii because
you're not using up your trips to Hawaii
you're creating new ones by going to
Hawaii okay
got it that's attachment what's identity
the pig and the rooster in the middle of
the Wheel of Life the pig is
misunderstanding nice clothes from the
mall
that's the pig the chicken wants to buy
nice clothes at the mall they think they
can find nice clothes at the mall
without sharing clothes with other
people that's chicken rooster okay Pig
is the idea that nice clothes don't come
from sharing nice clothes then chicken
is you know if you're a lady when you go
to the mall you get some extra money you
head for the mall you walk around for
3-4 hours you can't find anything
nothing fits
nothing looks right you spend the whole
day at the mall you come back with
nothing
okay then some day these friends says
you want to go to the mall get a coffee
okay then you see three beautiful things
on the way and you buy them like it's
like it doesn't make sense you know you
go to find something you can't find
anything you've got to have a coffee you
find three things okay
that's the emptiness of damoff okay
you're attached by the way you are the
snake thank you you had a snake anger if
you get upset when you go to the mall
and you spend three hours and you don't
find anything okay by the way I'm going
to tell the men how to go to the mall
okay just before you go have two coffees
and wear comfortable shoes when you get
to the mall eat a Cinnabon get lots of
sugar in your body and then just learn
to why they don't put chairs in those
stores I don't know you learn to sit on
the floor in the corner of the store
and you can meditate while the ladies
trying to pick out something that she
won't find if she doesn't have karma
anyway I tell my people think I just
teach Britain well I teach them all
awesome okay so in this case desire
desire means miss understanding your own
understanding
okay that's desire okay so don't don't
have an unhappy life without nice
clothes okay I like candy lies she
dresses really nice she makes up really
nice and she's a really good person at
the same time that's perfect okay that's
fine why not look nice it makes other
people happy okay all right so in the
diamond cutter Sutra when they say
attachment don't forget it means you
think that things coming without sharing
or you think you're not getting it just
bad luck it's not done it's not you
didn't share okay got it
then that you don't have your attachment
and you don't have hatred you don't have
pigs neg or chicken okay another thing
that happens if you understand that your
understandings are coming from sharing
it's implied that you understand you can
lose your understandings okay you can
lose your understanding everybody in
this room has a lot of faith they came
here from far countries many of them
okay and that face because it's coming
from you you kind of lose it and there
are many people who sat in this room for
five years seven years and are gone okay
and they're just doing nothing now they
don't care about Buddhism they're doing
something else
okay and I will get an email from them
when the doctor tells him they have
cancer I get all these emails I got one
you know I get them every day I got
cancer help me I said well where were
you for the last five years there twenty
five retreats where were you you know oh
I was busy so now you want me to help
you it's too late okay got it
just try to the implication of this
section is that you can lose your
understanding your faith is also coming
from your karma your understanding is
also coming from your karma it will wear
out if you don't hear okay you will lose
it and you don't lose it you know you
don't suddenly grow horns on your head
it's not like that you just say oh I
think I'll skip this alarm image I'll
catch the next one
you know then the process starts because
you lost your seats okay you sit are
wearing out okay and that ties into this
this section which is work hard work
hard you can't stop you can't say oh I
understand emptiness now I don't have to
read GenCon Jing anymore okay you have
to keep going because you have to share
okay
so in lasting kumla Sheila's by the way
usually misunderstanding things creates
clashes creates negative emotions
misunderstanding your husband is the
hurdle field for feeling angry at your
husband
okay but it says be careful because the
opposite could happen right about your
understanding can also cause negative
emotions you know you rock in your
husband yells at you like I understand
you're just coming for me go to hell you
know then then your understanding
created negative emotions okay so be
careful clients are very I recall grease
pig greased pig means a small pig you
put oil on them hard to catch like a
diamond mountain mouse difficult to
catch okay
those Mouse's have been through many
three-year retreats they know how to
ruin a ridge right what was that okay
bye wait I'm just going to keep going
till we finish where we have to go so we
might take another break okay
now meditation number four here's the
Sutra the Buddha is talking I'll conquer
the fact that I can feel this way about
this future the fact that I believe to
believe in your Sutra that's not a big
surprise that's not a big thing
okay but when I think about the future
and the last 500 years of your teaching
which is happening now okay it started
around 2000 okay that's the call we call
the last 500 years of the Buddhist
teaching we are in the last major period
of Buddhism on this world and it will
die after that according to Buddha okay
so he says when I think about people who
show up during the last years of your
teaching in this world and they believe
in it man those aren't cool people those
are over the top over the top they are
like beyond cool okay I can't even
imagine those people you know when
Buddhism is dying and the whole world is
burning and they are going hugging the
west desert in the world your legs you
got Jim you know dust people man they're
amazing you know they leave their
comfortable home in Germany and flied to
Arizona to get sunburn and dust and wild
pigs and roxas
cactus and cactus doc boy those guys are
cool okay
the booty is looking ahead to at you
okay and don't don't think Buddhists
like to feel guilty they like to feel
their insufficient serious Buddhist
people like to say cash line I'm not not
a good person like shopping always tell
me that okay so I'm not a good person
you know yeah okay go get me 500 more
coffees you know okay you know then
after you read this part of this Sutra
you can't think like that anymore okay
don't get proud don't get arrogant don't
get you know unpleasant but you're a
special I'm sorry
okay yeah a super special person okay
why I put chicken chicken eater right
this is this chicken chicken is sorry
not chicken answer they think it's a new
KFC this is how do you think okay tikka
Itza
this is in Mexico this is in Mexico
it's a ancient building and they call it
one of the wonders of the world
okay that's sometimes seven wonders of
the world eight wonders of the world
most amazing place in the world most
amazing thing in the world why did I put
that picture because you are chicken
eater so you tell me what it say again
teach him
yeah like he said okay you are you are
wonder of the world
yeah whatever wandering around okay what
are they one of the world babylon temple
of daemon chicken itza and me okay like
I'm I'm amazing okay
what's Jame Brown say I'm so cool I
could kiss myself okay so in this
meditation do this meditation okay I
know you're all going to skip this you
people who who can't do coffee
meditation you're three steppers I'm
gonna split that one I don't want to be
nice to myself if you can't be nice to
yourself you can't be nice to other
people not possible okay if you can't
appreciate yourself you can't appreciate
other people it won't happen okay
sometimes you know meditate about how
goddamn lucky I am you know I'm I'm
amazing
okay I made it to Diamond this is the
holiest place I mean next to Safeway
it's amazing place okay I made it today
okay alright then during this meditation
I want you to think about all the Dharma
things you've done okay maybe three
years ago you memorize some prayer you
know in the laundry room you remember I
said when I came to sixth retreat
somebody told me from China this is
number six that's amazing then think
about it okay you know there's so many
other things you can do you know so so
many other
you can go on vacation you know you can
go to five movies in a row you know and
you could go shopping indefinitely
especially on Orchard Road in Singapore
but you're here and you you you get many
many good things so think about during
this meditation
I don't know spend 15 minutes then half
hour play back the video of the cold
Dharma stuff you did those of you who
did to your retreat I don't know about
you I kind of forgot about my speech it
I can't remember what happened but I
know I did it so yeah so be happy about
it you know playback the video playback
the hard times playback the good times
and say I did it you know god damn I did
it you know I made it tear through
everything I must be somebody either the
biggest fool in Arizona you know yeah I
got company so appreciate yourself
sometimes okay you're amazing
you organizing programs for 7,000 people
the last two weeks we are on tour in
7,000 people that's your hard work okay
that's amazing
it's amazing to get seven people seven
thousand I can't imagine it's amazing
okay it's cool okay all right so I'm
sorry
in this section you have to be happy
about yourself okay
next meditate
the main point of the next section of
diamond cutter Souter is that Buddha has
only Buddha has the capacity to see all
things and to see their emptiness at the
same time okay without alternating at
the same time Buddha can see all things
and when Buddha looks at them Buddha
sees where they're coming from
what did he do to create those things
okay so Buddha has our capacity to see
that they're not coming from their own
sign at the same time that he looks at
them so on this one is kind of similar
to the one about breakfast and the
universe during this meditation I like
to just I mean I like to read science
fiction novels they're called space
operas James it's kind of just like
daytime television but it's in outer
space
so I like to read the story they're
still like romances and stuff like that
but they they're in different worlds
different planets people are flying in
spaceships and so sometimes go outside
at Dinah mountain look up which you
can't do in Shanghai Guangzhou mostly
and look at the Stars and think about I
made those okay and there are people on
those some of those stars have people
living there and I made them and let
your mind go into the sky that's why I
remoteness is a nice place to do retreat
in my three-year retreat I used to climb
up on the yurt and lay down on it and
try not to slide off hang on to the dome
thing and do my mantras and look at the
Stars
so I strung I did it yesterday I just
sat out on the porch it was a the
evenings are beautiful right now
okay there's one week of good weather
every year done mom this is it so enjoy
you know go out on the porch watch the
Sun go down then watch the Stars come
out and think let your mind go out there
and imagine at the same time that you
created them okay and let your mind go
when you're feeling down or you have
moon your chest feels tight the people
are making I don't know people are
making you upset traffic bad drivers
make me upset I can't stop it
these are sitting next to me saying
where they come from ready Campari soda
quiet fine
don't give me that British stuff this a
bad grammar you know and life is better
life is full of let's just you know and
just let it go that's why you're here
use use the sky at dynamo okay use it
it's here you paid a lot of money it's
probably costing like $100 every star
just enjoying you know like just relax
tonight evening sit on the porch watch
the Sun go down do some mantras you know
sometimes you are doing great practice
when you are just relaxing and do some
mantras watch the star I just love to
watch the Sun go down here
and there's a soft wind and the stars
come out and it's just really really
nice okay and then think about I made
those stars okay all right this
meditation is not very difficult well
maybe it is for some people okay next
one
it's called facing the fear of emptiness
and I'll read the future to you okay and
when's the booty had spoken these words
the conquer spoke to this Junior monks
the booty as solos
also booty thus it is and thus is it
very this in some of our materials this
is misspelled it supposed to be thus th
us not thi s okay thus it is and thus
isn't in a living being who receives an
explanation of this Sutra and who is not
made afraid and it's not terrified and
who does not become terrified it's
amazing okay anyone who can listen to
this suture and not get scared it's
amazing okay
then it's a little scary to think that
all the stars are coming from you it's
easy to think if nothing exists then I
don't exist or maybe the whole worlds in
my head you know it's not okay good I
never said that are the stars images in
your mind yes do they exist outside yes
answer yes to both okay are they in your
mind yes are they real
yes do you have to take a spaceship to
get to there yes do they exist millions
of miles away yes okay they're not
everything in your mind all right
it's out your mind made it outside Karen
we talked about that okay so in that's
what enter the school right there's a
distinction between the emptiness of
people and the emptiness of things in
the highest goal not no distinction
about the quality of the emptiness or
how difficult it might be mostly so a
Swanton toka like Camila Sheila is going
to read this part as you know it's a
little hard to push beyond the emptiness
of me James and push it to everything
you know you know it feels uncomfortable
I can understand the emptiness of
Michael Michaels understanding
understand the emptiness and Michael's
understanding because it comes from
sharing I understand that but you know
the world is empty these rocks are
emptied the calculators the people
everybody around me the temple the floor
the carpet all those things are empty
that's a little scary
okay because Carla Sheila says if you
start to go there that all the stuff
around me is empty you might include
yourself and then you get lost oh
there's no me you know if if I
understand my understanding is empty and
I understand it comes from seeds or
sharing King country but if you say that
the carpet that I'm sitting on is empty
if you say the temple is empty if you
say my laptop is empty my phone is empty
my Internet's empty then I must be empty
- and I don't exist and that's
frightening
okay that's the lady in this picture
looks frightened no she's like this
see this got it
you know if I'm empty that means I
control the future
okay if if I'm also empty scary not
scary fun you know wow I can have
anything you know I can get money I can
have good health I can have a nice
marriage my meditation can be perfect
forever I can help the whole world Wow
because why because I'm empty because
things are empty she understands
emptiness okay so Britta is saying in
this section people who don't understand
emptiness get scared all right
everything's empty I'm empty I'm not
here then how can I brush my teeth like
that okay
I'm empty all day that's so cool now I
can be I can have everything you know
next year it's going to be 2017 it's
gonna be the best year in my life okay
because things are empty things can go
wrong any moment okay because things are
coming from your karma your hand can be
a dog top five minutes from now okay if
it's coming this way it will take a few
hours if it's coming from you from your
seeds you can be barking before the Sun
Goes Down today okay if it's empty
it scared that's scary okay bad things
can happen
you're driving to Tucson you just had
two nice retrieves you finally
understood something bear truck hits
your car you're all dead then you're
somewhere between stars you know oh look
I made this time
[Music]
okay so it's scary it's a little bit
scary if things are coming from my mind
then bad things can happen in two
minutes two minutes my whole life can
change in a few minutes one you like
twelve inches from these big charts you
know someone's means you're dead it's
scary it's frightening okay
karma can go like that but you can the
opposite is also true
you can every problem you're having
right now in your life can become the
coolest thing in your life in one week
okay
all the people you hate the most your
job your finances your health it can
change in a week okay if you know how to
plant seeds then that's cool so don't
focus on the big truck gonna kill you
focus on I can make anything happen
because I'm creating it okay if I can
create the star if I can make planets I
can make my boss smile it makes me okay
I got in so it shouldn't be scared you
should be happy okay if things are not
empty you have a problem okay then you
should be miserable and scared
I wrote in my notes I always think about
the Titanic movie I think it's the most
popular movie of all time and I think
it's because it's so it's so poignant
those were the most wealthy people in
the world at that time on that boat in
England and America they were the most
wealthy people and they got to go on the
biggest boat ever made the fastest
journey to America and on that boat they
had big bars and there are smoking
cigars and they are drinking the best
alcohol and then ten minutes later
they're in the water ice water and most
of them are dead
ten minutes later half an hour later you
know so life can go like that you can
watch if you don't believe me watch the
movie right okay and and I made myself
and no don't forget you you have you
have special ways to make good karma if
you want you can juice up your good
karma you can make your good cover much
stronger how you can do therefore
internet thoughts you know you can say
I'm eating this breakfast for all the
living beings in this part of the galaxy
you can do that okay that's a fast way
to make good karma in Tantra in sick of
Buddhism you try to imagine that
everybody around you might be a Buddha
already okay you try to imagine that and
if you want to make powerful mood life
if you want your life to change from
from this week forever
you can think that you don't need
tantric initiation to think that way
okay it's just logical that there's been
Buddhism for many years in the world
some people must have practiced it well
so some people must be Buddha already
and they're all maybe they're around me
maybe one of my friends into Buddha okay
and when you think like that you make
very good kamma okay and then and then
you can be happy about the future the
next 2017 is going to be amazing
I got Buddhist around me helping me all
day Wow it's gonna be a good year okay
like that but if you understand it don't
be proud about it don't get excited and
think it's coming from you it's coming
because you helped other people in the
test okay you guys okay you don't need a
break right okay
next meditation guess what we reached a
famous story of the king of calling car
okay
and I worked on it pretty hard and
you're gonna like it so just enjoy relax
okay here we go
by the way this is 13th part of Camila
Sheila's parts and it's called biology
manana Daniela Jimmy Amba means ignoring
pain that comes during your Buddhist
practice learning to ignore pain that
comes during your Buddhist practice the
dust storm comes up you're covered with
dirt in your retreat cottage
this sections about I don't give a damn
I don't care I'm meditating
if the cottage falls down I don't care
when I started my three retreat nama
Elma we were living in tents because our
cottages weren't finished and the wind
took her a tent and put it on the top of
a very tall oak tree removing it and try
to get that thing down I'm going on then
this sections about I don't give it I
don't care I'm tough guy
I'm Dharma tough guy ok problems will
come when you practice time up problems
will come when you don't practice Dharma
worst problems will come which one is
better so then this part it's pretty
amazing section it starts when Lord
Buddha sense
let's forget talking about perfection of
wisdom let's talk about the perfection
of patience not getting angry not
getting upset I don't like to call it
patience why I looked it up on my
royalty-free non-free photo site and
when you type in patience you get people
who can wait in long lines without
getting angry but that's not what this
means this means someone calls you
stupid someone criticizes you someone
hurts you someone hits you and you said
you don't get angry okay we should call
it the perfection of don't get angry
okay all right then Britta says the
perfection of patience which the
Buddhists teach doesn't even exist
that's the next part of the diamond
cutter Sutra patience
doesn't exist okay and then we reached
the story of the king of kalinga okay
Colin Carr was a famous area of ancient
India it was a kingdom okay but one
author one sanskrit scholar named
Edgington who's a great sanskrit scholar
who was my chance with teachers teacher
he says it's connected to colleague
Roger Kali means black or evil usually
okay Roger means King so he says
colleague car raja comes from Cali Raja
meaning evoking bad King okay then
it's a guy with a knife he's threatening
you okay and it has into patients it's
like cement the more you get pressed the
stronger it gets
okay cement has cool quality dr. Stumpf
can tell you the first day you pour
cement you can break it easily
okay then every day there's a chemical
reaction inside and it goes on for years
I think and the cement gets harder and
harder and harder okay so most things
get weaker every year but cement is the
strength you know for many years or for
a couple years it will get harder every
year okay that's why it's hard to break
old pieces of cement okay it just gets
harder every year now if you understand
emptiness your ability to put up with
irritating people should get stronger
and stronger and stronger the more your
husband attacks you the better you feel
you know come on give it to me you
stupid oh yeah okay give me another
one yeah boom oh come on give me you
know
then your patient gets stronger because
your emptiness holds trunk normal
patients without emptiness will reach a
breaking point always okay if you don't
understand emptiness there's a place
well you you will hit back okay okay let
me boom okay huh him again boom yeah him
again boom yeah boom your patients book
break okay if you don't understand
emptiness your patient to a break at
some point your patients will break even
between countries push push push
okay push push push okay push push push
war now we're gonna have a war okay if
someone blow up your biggest building
yeah no I'm gonna kill you you know like
that you reach a place where some push
you too far you will get angry okay but
a Buddhist is like cement not mentally
your Buddhism gets stronger the more
people push you okay someone push you
you're like yeah okay I'm a Buddhist it
doesn't bother me
then push you then like I told you I'm a
Buddhist you know think so we're really
pushing anything you're empty you're
empty bring then it's endless
the push push push empty empty empty you
know and your patients get strongest
your patients grow faster than your
anger okay you just get like cement
patient get harder the more people
attack you small attack you can forget
emptiness big attack you're like what's
happening why does happening Oh
emptiness okay okay got it
Buddhist patience is endless it gets
stronger than more people attack you
okay
so during this meditation you're going
to think of times recently when someone
hurt you
someone attacked you someone took
something or broke something of yours
okay
someone didn't do what they said they
would do and you're gonna practice being
patient with them okay I'll come from me
came from me so for each irritating
person in your life you're going to try
to find out what did I do to make you
okay here's normal person when someone
calls them stupid you're stupid
no you're stupid here's the Buddhist
you're stupid you're you know if you
want to insult your friends at Diamond
Mountain when they do something stupid
you can go like this it means where did
this idiot come from how did I make this
idiot when someone go like this at that
mountain
you should feel in talk well how did I
make you all right mmm next meditation
number eight
this is so wife yelling at the husband
it feels like that right sometimes the
guys know it feels like the woman has a
megaphone only their wife nothing man
when the wagon angry is my ball you know
I'm militant you know
then during this meditation there's a
one two three four five six points here
there's no patience there's no
perfection of patience no one's being
patient there's no one I'm being patient
towards there's no stupid thing my wife
did that I'm being patient about and if
I succeed in this patience it's also
gonna be because I shared this teaching
with other people something like that
okay so I want you to go through
patience with somebody you're having a
little bit of trouble with right now
this okay all of us it's human nature
it's the nature and sansara
that most the times in your life there's
one person you're having a little
trouble with okay then do the six parts
with them that's all you don't need me
to explain it
then Buddha says let's take a real
example and then he takes the story of
the king of calling cuff okay
and meditation number nine that's not
Donald Trump that's that's that's us
when we're upset okay
when someone's bothering us you are like
a grumpy little baby okay
some of you studied might reyes
flowchart for sons honor some of you
studied might reyes flowchart for
samsara okay
this is Kamala Sheila's version okay
very similar you know this causes this
this causes this this causes this this
causes this this causes Dayton I get
upset okay and by the way he took it
from Dom acuity so Adams translating
Dharma Kitty nowadays the great logician
of ancient India okay I'll read you the
poem from Dharma Katie okay this is what
Kamla Sheila uses and he credits her
maturity those who think there is a self
begin to conceive of something other or
somebody other and because they
distinguish between me and you they
start to protect me and they start to
dislike you and then all the problems of
a human life come from that I'll say it
again this is delicately okay if you
think things are not empty if you think
they have self nature then you can start
to think there's a some other person if
you think they're to me self existent
then of course you're going to start
thinking there's a you
if there's a mediator you when you start
to distinguish between me and you then
you start to protect me and dislike you
and then comes all the problems of your
life okay because you thought their to
me which is not coming from your seats
right okay now let's go back to the
camera Sheila broke it down for us okay
number one I am myself I control my
thoughts I control my body they are not
coming out of seats they are not coming
from how I treat other people okay my
body my mind will be the same whether I
treat other people good or bad okay
that's ignorant okay it's not true your
mind is coming from what you hear inside
your head all day how well you can
understand things how well you can
meditate coming from seeds being nice to
other people okay
the condition of your body how healthy
you are it doesn't come from yoga it
doesn't come from eating well that's why
I have coffee it's coming from how do
you take care of others health okay
don't drink coffee
okay so miss understand where you're
coming from
then you can be number two you to be
attached to me okay I'm billion I have
to take care of Vivian I should come
billions here I don't have to come
Jenny's here too much trouble one hair -
no no hair is also bad okay then
me against others I should get I should
look nice today I don't care if jasmine
looks nice today
I should look nice to me okay you spend
time
in the bathroom you know with the makeup
you know I should look nice today if
Jasmine looks nice today it's okay I
don't care but she has to take care of
that I'm not going to take care of that
okay then you start to kill me me and
I'm not Jasmine she has to take care of
her own this thing it's enough trouble
for me to take care of mine okay then
desire comes I this is the usual kind of
desire I should look good and I don't
care if other people longer number six
is very important listen I don't know if
you guys notice English we reported my
my desire is courted it means somebody
did something to stop me from getting
what I want something did some somebody
what I want are you addicted to coffee
no geshe-la are just enjoying good
because because David drank all your
coffee what that's a sign you're
addicted okay when someone stops you
from getting something and then you get
really upset that design if you liked it
okay so that's number six someone hurt
me someone hurt me I didn't get what I
wanted I wanted coffee
David drank all the coffee David hurt me
then from that comes all the problems of
life okay
okay mmm by the way come on uh Sheila
says he's just talking about one kind of
negative thought which is anger or a
feeling upset but of course he's talking
about all kinds of negative thoughts
okay this is the diamond cutter Sutras
too short to cover the 84,000 negative
thoughts that you have we just pick one
okay
all right last part today if you have to
pee pee go pee pee no problem mastered
Camelot Sheila says there's three things
that can make you upset he just gives
three examples
we're on meditation number ten what's
happening in the picture yeah you gave
your seed to an old lady I tried for
like an hour to find a photo I couldn't
then I found a cartoon okay this girl
gave her seat on the bus to an old lady
okay
this meditation is called have I
practiced patience three times in the
last 24 hours
patience towards three things okay
Camila Sheila says patients can come
towards three things number one when
someone hurt me did I let it go okay
someone did something to hurt me that
criticized me they took something I
wanted they didn't let me get something
I wanted in the last 24 hours
did someone hurt you okay and did you
practice patience okay did you let it go
or not
okay did you let it go second
did I accept pain or inconvenience for
my practice inconvenience for your
practice means you stand up the whole
bus ride and the old lady gets to sit
down I got really offended in Beijing or
Guangzhou I got on the bus to the
airport and some young mayor gave me his
seat would you like to sleep no I'm not
that all right so it hurts to stand up
the whole bus line okay it's
inconvenient okay so in the last 24
hours
did you happily put up with some
inconvenience for your practice okay
you know I went home tonight my cabin
didn't have electricity or water right
then in then did you say in your mind
this is really stupid retreat center or
did you say I'm a Buddhist I'm here to
practice I don't care if the whole house
falls down I'm tough guy I'm dumb a
tough guy okay
like did you meditate that night or you
all night you see I don't have
electricity I don't know watch me okay
okay then
it means if you're gonna be a Buddhist
if you're gonna follow this path
sometimes you just gotta in English if
they suck it up suck it up means tuck it
on I don't care okay you know the food
is like the worst I tasted in last ten
years
okay I'm meditating okay I'm not saying
the food is bad just giving example like
healthy food tastes terrible okay final
thing
good I have the first two kinds of
patients with people who hurt me and
with my practice because I understood
that the things that hurt me are coming
from me or was I just being a tough guy
okay
when the electricity went out of my
house and the water stopped was I just
being hard-ass Buddhist or did I really
understand why it happened to me and not
to anybody else in the whole retreat
valley okay did I remember to think
about why this person's hurting me or
why my electricity went out did I stop
just before I called Michael done did I
did I stop for one minute and think
about why why me okay why me that's the
third kind of patience the object of the
three kinds of patience number one
people who bother you who hurt you
number two difficulties when you're
trying to be Buddhist you know
sub-problem come okay number three life
okay the object of places number three
is a whole life everything good things
bad things all coming from you anything
that's coming from you come Lucido cause
it surprised she the kolchak Akashi not
power you know the fun what it is that
you're being patience toward what are
you being patient about number one
number two difficulties in your practice
days when the meditation doesn't go well
okay number three
Ryan hold on be patient okay got it
now there was a kid quotation by Kimora
Sheila I thought it was so beautiful I
put it in your meaning okay
if you are unwilling to do the things
that are difficult to do then you can't
expect to reach the state which is
difficult to reach okay
getting to Buddhahood is difficult it's
made of many difficult practices if you
don't want to do difficult practices you
can't reach the place that you get to by
doing this it's like a diet okay I can
tell you if you're not willing to eat
food that tastes bad for two weeks
then don't expect to lose weight okay
they're just that's the way it is okay
if you say I just want to eat punch eggs
yo tell turtle how come I know that word
in every language if you just want to
have fun it's not going to work okay
it's just not going to work
sometimes you have to do hard things to
get to a cool place okay
all right doing yoga is hard I don't
like it I really don't like it but I
want to be healthy okay so I do it you
just do it okay my llama like Dirty
Harry movies you guys don't know you're
too young Dirty Harry's American police
heroes he shoot everybody you know he's
got a gun against some guy you know the
guy has a gun he has a gun he's like
that and he and he says he looks the guy
in the eye says I want to have a good
day just just hear me I want to have a
good day
it means I'm going to shoot you you know
he's tough guy then I saw him in a
television show and this lady you know
these television ladies that I not like
Vivian okay she's a good television
thing
but they're like oh you're so strong and
handsome you know how do you get those
done you know he says I exercise she
says oh I know ever all of our audience
wants to learn to exercise then can you
tell us your secret how do you access
art every day how can you get the real
power to exercise every day and then
he's like this he says I do it she says
can you tell us more no I do it but it
has to be like that how you going to
meditate how do you mean yeah how are
you become identification and then I do
it tell us more no I do it I just do it
ok ok cool now you are lucky because
last thing today I'm going to tell you
the whole story of king of calling car
the real story ok it comes from benaiah
ready
so just enjoying you don't have to learn
anything
mom's going to tell your story ok so
once upon a time there was a king a king
called Tom okay Tom okay means born in
strife born in times of fighting because
he was born in Varanasi I went there
with candy and shopping this year he was
born in Varanasi during a time of civil
disturbance there was some fighting
going on in Varanasi which happened
still every week and sorry his name when
their Queens were voting for his name
they decided to come born from hassle
hassle born or something like that
okay Tom okay okay
yeah so yeah his father and his mother
had a good time together which is how
the Sutra says they have sex okay they
say they don't say have sex they say
they had a good time together then
always there's a baby after that then
after eight or nine months a baby came
out on the day he was born in water
nursing there was a disturbance people
fighting with each other so when the
Queens got together to choose a name
they decided to call him born during the
fighting and talk smells so good did
Obama know one day when he became king
it was springtime and he and his Queens
decided to go out to the forest because
it was the time of the flowers opening
like the Oh Katya flowers here very
beautiful right now and it was the time
of non bottom to modulate Sarika kucik
and Shang Shang to you which means lots
of different kinds of births with people
okay in my cabin girls count and they
make a lot of beautiful song is it
everywhere I don't know yes beautiful
songs in the morning okay number means
dark tinting means cream margin means
peacock metal means parents read cake I
have no idea who took is another kind of
parrot
and some junk to you is a they call
those the guys with the sting on their
head running around with their kids
quail quail okay okay there was singing
so the king and the queens got in the
mood to go out for a walk and they went
for a walk
they went so far that the king got tired
and sat down in front of a tree and fell
asleep he took a nap
the Queen's kept going picking flowers
and went pretty far away then they found
a Buddhist monk was meditating under a
tree and they said wow this is cool we
met a real meditator then they said can
you teach us to do that you know can you
teach us how to meditate we like it and
they all sat down around the month then
his name was super mama
which means Shanti rotten it means
master of patience never gets angry okay
his name is mister and never gets angry
okay then he taught them shemitah he's
teaching them how to meditate then of
course the King woke up he look around
his queens are all missing he said
something happened to my queen and he
pulled out his sword and he went to find
out who kidnapped his queens you know
doctor non-vented my lumina mr. Dharma
then he came upon a clearing and here's
this monk sitting with all his queens
around them looking very interested then
talked okay what start off without
jealous he got jealous okay
ninety-two they committed and I think it
turns out there to know someone I didn't
came up to the monk you know and the he
was so angry that the Queen's run away
Dale ran oh they know him they said we
better not stick around they ran away
then they they the King said what's your
name and the monk said I mister patience
okay
then the king said we'll see how patient
you are and he started to cut his
fingers off okay one by one then they
cut off a couple of fingers then he said
excuse me what was your name again then
he said my name is mr. patience says
well we'll just have to see then he cut
his hand okay and his feet yeah and then
okay you know I mean you know nothing
about dating cetera
then among set a poem okay I'll read L
take back a little on me killing dudes
on the to PE you can cut my body into
pieces as small as little I'll give you
a clue till oppa till means are sesame
seed the black sesame see we offer in
the fire small see you can cut my body
into this many pieces okay no michi my
gardener you can cut me into 100 pieces
solid torque young you can throw them
all over the forest
show me palm I don't give up I don't get
upset
I'm mister patients okay Concha doc each
um doc each I'm game where I suddenly
thought to come today because I have
love for you okay you can cut me up I
don't care I love you okay
prodota Lackawanna I see you with more
love than a mother has for her own son
okay
separate separate they don't throw a man
I don't I don't need to give up patience
I love you okay six each other young dad
I'm sorry Sonny
then we'll end up at Samba you know they
are demeaning you're not the United took
the dark surfer dime yeah but Donna sent
you to give a garroted attack you know
it's not something I have defeated my
negative emotions because I understand
emptiness anonymity you're just helping
me become a Buddha then I attack you
back with the perfection of wisdom
you're attacking me with a sword I
attack you back with the perfection of
wisdom
okay I understand who you are I
understand where you're coming from and
every time I every time I hit you back
with my sword of problem is off then I
lose more clashes I'm cutting my own
negativities okay that's my response to
you Gallaudet and details on Geneva
meetings then there you are the whole
story you know mine so there was local
spirits like at Diamond Mountain okay we
had a lot of local spirits they were
walking this whole thing that humans
can't see them but they are in the
forest and they're like wow check that
out
he's cutting off his head Wow he cut off
Wow
he's throwing up feeding the hands in
the fourth wow that's unbelievable
mmm the mug didn't do anything wrong
he was just trying to help the cream you
know
and look how patient he is wow that's so
cool
then they took a vow cupcake we don't
promote a Yankee soldier donkey Adam
Jones Edgington so I could tell where
gig got some chicks they went up to the
monk the Spirit came to the monk you
know just give me the word just say do
it I will destroy the King I will
destroy his kids I will destroy his
family I will destroy his city and I
will destroy his country just say do it
he told the monk just say do it I'm
ready
this guy's a bad King let's bring him
down you know okay guess what the most
said that the center says he pwned the
spirit doc honey darling
chunky dollar lopper combat down nah nah
tell him Martin check your parc guel on
departure Feynman dinner
me meadow another multi good you know
that guy cut off my hands that guy cut
off my legs that guy cut off my nose he
hurt me but I don't even want to hurt
him much less his innocent family
innocent kids innocent City innocent
country I don't even want to hurt the
guy who hurt me
why should I want to hurt the whole
country or hurt his family they didn't
do anything okay then that the spirit
didn't listen to him young connect he
brought a what you calling when the
whole country gets the same sickness he
brought up saying like Egypt and rats
came and chair was came and I don't know
what to tell her I couldn't find it I
guess it's a big round I don't know and
he sent these nasty birds and they came
down like they fell from the sky
all these animals and began to kill
people
okay then that Kings called when he call
his seer seers people understand the
future okay and he said you know what's
going on why why these animals falling
on the sky
killing all our people you know what's
what's the cause of me and they said you
cut up mr. patience that's the cause you
know he didn't do anything so because of
that the local spirits are upset at you
and at us okay then that King said wow
we should try to you know settle this so
he said to the seers let's make some
torment and some flower garlands just
like we do here and other things and
let's ask the spirits you know we're
sorry and we apologize
then the King went out to the city and
said everyone should make time us and
that's this problem was caused by me
because I was jealous and I apologized
him everyone should try to make time us
everyone should try to make the spirits
happy and I will also go to the monk and
ask him for he what he call beg his
forgiveness I will ask forgiveness okay
so the king went to the monk mr.
patience and he touched his feet but I
think it's a mistake because he didn't
have any
I was like what is not and he said you
know I'm really sorry I got upset I saw
you with my Queens I was thought you
were doing something bad and will you
give me your forgiveness and and that
mountain gave a poem back nihlus indeed
up yep UNAM dog nice ending could not
jump Celtic you meet in a dark dark dark
dark burrata he said there's nothing to
forgive you for because I never got
upset it didn't bother me you'll cut off
my hands it's night then you don't have
to ask me to forgive you
because I'm not upset and if you don't
believe me check out the blood and he
held up his hand arm you know and the
Bloods coming up but it's milk okay it's
milk is coming up said I'm not I don't
have a problem look milks coming on then
the King still a chip on my gear he
stood in and belief that this is special
person who didn't get upset he still
thinks he has to ask for forgiveness
ok he said but let me let me ask you for
forgiveness then the monks getting
impatient and he said if it's true then
I never got angry with you during that
whole incident may my body come back
together no more all his parts came back
ok then the King got big eyes well came
a chilly night night there came out -
dude you didn't get a lil October
Japan ancilla me got tea army now I
believe
you didn't get upset and off you know
the whole time you'll just play with me
you could have put your body back
together anytime okay now I believe that
you didn't get upset you are really mr.
patience okay then everybody touch their
feet their head to his feet now now it's
possible okay
now you're ready for the punch line
Buddhist telling this story to the monks
right then he says who do you think that
monk was that was me that was my past
life okay I was the monk mr. patience I
I wasn't a Buddha yet but I was a monk
named mr. patients who understand
emptiness so didn't get angry okay then
I think the cold punchline he says guess
who the king was called vineya vineya
you learn cut vineyard in the lamrim he
was there when the Buddha taught the
first term he's the head of the fire
okay he said best monk of the first five
students and that monk is the tigress
the woman Tiger the mommy tiger okay
cool
dim window when he was cutting his arms
and he hate Buddha so much he hate mr.
patient so much mr. patient said I'm
gonna ride that connection I'm going to
use that connection you know you cut my
hands you cut my legs you're gonna be a
tiger in the future and I'm going to
save your life and that can I'm going to
ride that connection and then you're
going to become my best duty
in the when I become a Buddha the first
person I teach is going to be you
because we have this karma no bad karma
we have a very tight connection
you cut my fingers off you cut my hands
off I will feed you with my body you
will eat my body and then you're stuck
man
then you're my student when I become a
Buddha
you are my first tournament because you
made this connection with me through
your hatred to your hatred okay so we're
going to do one last meditation ready
during this meditation you're going to
think about someone who hurts you a lot
okay in your life okay it's a difficult
choice you have to think of people who
hurt you in this line okay oh that one
hurt me pretty bad that one hurt me
pretty bad okay that one's hurting me
now okay I was thinking about it there's
this a guy on the Internet
he spent all day writing stuff about me
bad stuff for many years still going you
know like just every day and now he
found out my friends names he talks bad
about and I think he sits in his room
all day long he's like studying whatever
I go what I do who I talked to and then
he writes something bad on this internet
you know and so I forgave him in a
Buddhist way you know I'm like I don't
care you know I'm not going to say
anything
you can attack me all day you just waste
your time it doesn't bother me but it
does bother me but I try to pretend it
doesn't bother me people say did you
read that thing I don't care it doesn't
bother me I want to talk about it okay
but still it bothers me okay so I'm
thinking I'm always trying to think of
new ways to check myself to like him but
it's difficult but when I read this
story I got an idea okay I think you're
gonna be my first student when I become
Bruna okay we're making connection on
the internet every day you are cutting
off my fingers on the internet you know
so that means we have a connection okay
every time you do that we get closer you
know every time you think about me even
negatively you are planting seed to meet
me again in the future so I'm going to
turn it around okay every time you write
someone Internet you know then in the
future you will have to eat my bunny
okay when you get really hungry I will
give you my body and then after that by
the power of our connection you are
going to do my first student when I
become Buddha you're gonna be my number
one student called Enya okay got it so I
suggest today during the meditation okay
I'll just be quiet which is unusual and
think about the person who hurt you the
most in this life okay it's not
difficult right you know who they are
usually it's an ex-wife or something
think about them and in your heart say
you are gonna buy the truth that we have
our karmic connection now because you
hurt me so bad
you're going to show up on time that
meditation for the rest of the week
maybe the rest of your life okay and say
by the power of our tight connection
because you hurt me so bad you must
become my first student okay you do
active truth okay active truth if it's
true that you hurt me so bad
then you must become my first student
when I become Buddha okay
deal deal ready and and let's see if it
changes our feeling about that person
okay maybe we can start to feel more
love for them okay all right here we go
just quiet for five minutes they will go
home and we're on schedule yeah
imagine becoming abouna maybe you're
sitting under a tree in a garden on this
world or another world and this person
comes in and they are your first student
they're the first person you teach after
you became Buddha
3d tech cells give away the good kamma
Gregg uncommon and you can open your
eyes take a strategy that's all for
today we are caught up